# JESÚS FERRÁNDIZ ALARCÓN

11th March 1998

- **(** +34 605 38 22 76
- ieferrandiz98@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/jesus-ferrandiz
- London, United Kingdom

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a robotics passionate always keen to further my knowledge. I am really interested in Computer Vision and Artificial Intelligence and I am experienced in both manipulation and mobile robotics due to my previous work with a collaborative rehabilitation robot, a lunar rover and a dexterous hand+arm. I count with more than 2.5 years of experience in:

- C++
- Python
- ROS/ROS2
- Ubuntu
- Controls and Motion Planning

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Team player
- · Self-learning spirit
- Strong time management
- Brainstorming and creative thinking
- Highly motivated
- Scientific and analytical mind
- Agile methodology
- Jira, Scrum

# **Work Experience**

- Robotics Software Engineer
  - Shadow Robot Company, London (Feb 2022 Currently)
  - **Commercial C++ and Python** development for the Shadow Hand and the teleoperation system. Unit tests, manipulation, planning, kinematics, QT GUI's and real time control.
  - Accountable for Software support of Shadow products.
  - Performance optimization, debugging.
- Robotics Software Intern

Space Applications Services, Brussels (Aug 2021 - Feb 2022)

- Implementing a **SLAM navigation architecture** for a Lunar Rover, including traversability mapping, Lidar/Depth camera PC processing, localization and path planning.
- Robotics Software Intern

Instituto Universitario de Automática e Informática Industrial (Oct 2020 - Jul 2021)

- Implemented a control architecture for **rehabilitation robots** based on **ROS2**, including position and force controllers.
- Author of **Q1 publication**, implemented controllers based on **Deep Reinforcement Learning** algorithms (TRPO and PPO) and worked with a motion capture system (**Optitrack**).

#### **Education**

 Master's Degree in Automation and Industrial Computing

Polytechnic University of Valencia (Oct 2020- Sept 2021)

- 10/10 on the Final Project and Special Mention
- Bachelor's Degree in Industrial Electronics and Automation Engineering

Polytechnic University of Valencia (2016-2020)

- **9.8 on the Final Project** which was based on implementing dynamic controllers for an industrial robot with a Real Time embedded system and an FPGA.
- 9.1/10 Average grade, awarded to best academic records of third year and achieved 16 Special Mentions.

### **Further Education**

- Self-Driving Cars Specialization University of Toronto 2023
- Mastering Data Structures & Algorithms C, C++ Udemy 2022
- Deep learning applied to signal and image analysis UPV 2021
- Intro to OpenCV app development UC3M 2020

## Languages

- English Fluent FCE B2, Cambridge English 2019
- Spanish Native

#### **Tech Skills**

- Fluent in C, C++ and Python
- Experienced in Linux, git, github, docker, ROS and ROS2
- · Machine Learning: Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-learn
- CV (2D/3D): Img processing, Segmentation, PCL, CNN
- · Experienced with C++ libraries: OpenCV, Eigen, PCL